Let's plot the relationship between two qualitative variables,
我们来绘制两个分类变量之间的关系
vehicle class and type of vehicle transmission.
汽车类型和汽车传动系统类型
To simplify things, I'm only going to look at the main type division.
为了叙述方便 我只研究两种主要类型
Automatic or manual, which has been stored in the trans_type column.
即列 trans_type 里记录的自动和手动型
One way of depicting this,
要绘制数据
could be with the heatmap like we saw before.
我们可以用之前见过的热图
There's actually a Seaborn function for
实际上 seaborn 有个函数可以创建
this categorical type of heatmap, the heatmap function.
分类变量的热图 即函数 heatmap
However, this function takes as an argument
但这个函数以
a 2D array or DataFrame with the values to be depicted.
一个由绘制数值组成的二维数组或 DataFrame 为参数
That means that we need to do some summarization
这就意味着我们要先汇总数据
work ourselves before we can create our plot.
之后才能创建图表
First, I use the groupby and size functions to get the number of cars
首先 我用函数 groupby 和 size 来获取两个变量
and each combination of the two variables levels as a panda series.
的各种类别组合及其对应的数量统计 并将其储存为 pandas Series
Then, I use reset index to convert the series into a DataFrame.
接着 用 reset_index 将 Series 转换成 DataFrame
Finally, I use pivot to rearrange the data so that I have vehicle class on rows,
最后 用 pivot 重塑数据 以汽车类型为行
transmission types on columns,
传动系统类型为列
and values in the cells.
将值写在单元格里
Now, we're ready to plot.
现在可以绘制了
This is actually kind of disappointing.
效果不怎么样
It's actually really hard to compare the counts and
因为单从颜色上看
transmission ratios from the colors alone.
我们很难比较传动系统的占比和数量统计
You can see that manual is less popular than automatic.
除了自动比手动更流行之外
But beyond that, it's kind of hard to tell.
其它信息都很难判断
One option we have is to add annotations with counts to
一种优化方法是 在单元格上标明统计值
the cells which makes the representation more tabular in nature.
这样一来 图表看起来更像一个表格
The fm 't' parameter set to 'd'
设参数 fmt 为 d
ensures that of all the counts are listed as decimal values.
从而确保所有数量统计都是十进制的
An alternative way of showing the distribution and
我们也可以用分组条形图
counts is through the use of a clustered bar chart.
来体现数据的分布和数量统计情况
In the last lesson, you saw how to use
上一章节已经介绍了
Seaborn's count plot function to generate a bar chart of one variable.
如何用 seaborn 的函数 countplot 来生成单变量条形图
To divide each of the individual bars into
要将各条形拆分成
multiple bars for the different transmission types,
多个条形 以便表示不同的传动系统
we just need to add a hue parameter pointing to the trans_type variable.
只需添加一个参数 hue 并为其赋值 trans_type 即可
With the cluster bar chart,
观察这个分组条形图
we can see clearly that mini compact cars have
不难发现微型车
the closest ratio between automatic and manual transmissions,
自动和手动传动系统的比例最接近
while large cars had the most distant ratio.
而大型车的比例则相差最远